{"id":"2017_16","name":"Romans2017_16","memoryVerse":"“He who did not spare his own Son, but gave him up for us all — how will he not also, along with him, graciously give us all things?” – Romans 8:32","dayQuestions":{"one":{"title":"FIRST DAY: Read the notes and the references.","questions":[{"id":"2017_16_1","questionText":"1. What was meaningful to you in the lecture?","answer":"","quotes":[]},{"id":"2017_16_2","questionText":"2. What help did you receive from the notes?","answer":"","quotes":[]}]},"two":{"title":"SECOND DAY: Read Romans 9:1-5.","readVerse":[{"book":"Romans","verse":"9:1-5"}],"questions":[{"id":"2017_16_3","questionText":"3.  What truth does Paul affirm? Why is Paul grieving for the people of Israel and how is he like Moses and Jesus? (For additional help see Exodus 32:30-32; Luke 19:41-44; John 10:11; Romans 9:1-29.) ","answer":"","quotes":[{"book":"Exodus","verse":"32:30-32"},{"book":"Luke","verse":"19:41-44"},{"book":"John","verse":"10:11"},{"book":"Romans","verse":"9:1-29"}]},{"id":"2017_16_4a","questionText":"4. a. Explain what “cursed” means in Romans 9:3 and whether any believer might ever be “cut off” from Christ. What do you think is Paul’s point? (See also Romans 8:1, 35, 38-39.)","answer":"","quotes":[{"book":"Romans","verse":"9:3"},{"book":"Romans","verse":"8:1"},{"book":"Romans","verse":"8:35"},{"book":"Romans","verse":"8:38-39"}]},{"id":"2017_16_4b","questionText":"4. b. How does Paul’s love for the unbelieving people of Israel model the way believers should respond to unbelievers?","answer":"","quotes":[]},{"id":"2017_16_5","questionText":"5. Consider the spiritual advantages God has given you. What are their benefits? How are they sometimes squandered? ","answer":"","quotes":[]}]},"three":{"title":"THIRD DAY: Read Romans 9:6-13.","readVerse":[{"book":"Romans","verse":"9:6-13"}],"questions":[{"id":"2017_16_6a","questionText":"6. a. How is God true to His Word despite the unbelief of the majority of the Israelite people?","answer":"","quotes":[]},{"id":"2017_16_6b","questionText":"6. b. What examples does Paul give to prove that physical birth never automatically makes anyone God’s child? (See also Romans 2:28-29.)","answer":"","quotes":[{"book":"Romans","verse":"2:28-29"}]},{"id":"2017_16_7","questionText":"7. How do these verses show salvation is by grace and not human effort? What hope does this give you for your unbelieving family members, friends or co-workers?  ","answer":"","quotes":[]}]},"four":{"title":"FOURTH DAY: Read Romans 9:14-21.","readVerse":[{"book":"Romans","verse":"9:14-21"}],"questions":[{"id":"2017_16_8","questionText":"8. What does Paul’s use of Bible history reveal about God and how He elects to work out His righteous and holy will? How does this compare with your understanding?  (See also Exodus 7:3, 13; 8:32; 14:4.) ","answer":"","quotes":[{"book":"Exodus","verse":"7:3"},{"book":"Exodus","verse":"7:13"},{"book":"Exodus","verse":"8:32"},{"book":"Exodus","verse":"14:4"}]},{"id":"2017_16_9a","questionText":"9. a. From verses 20-21, explain in your own words the problem with people accusing God of injustice. (See also Isaiah 29:16; 64:8; Jeremiah 18:6; 2 Timothy 2:20.)","answer":"","quotes":[{"book":"Isaiah","verse":"29:16"},{"book":"Isaiah","verse":"64:8"},{"book":"Jeremiah","verse":"18:6"},{"book":"2 Timothy","verse":"2:20"}]},{"id":"2017_16_9b","questionText":"9. b. Give examples of how people today (perhaps even you) use similar reasons to excuse sin or accuse God of injustice.","answer":"","quotes":[]},{"id":"2017_16_10","questionText":"10. How has God shown you mercy when your heart was hard, and how have you responded to Him? ","answer":"","quotes":[]}]},"five":{"title":"FIFTH DAY: Read Romans 9:22-29.","readVerse":[{"book":"Romans","verse":"9:22-29"}],"questions":[{"id":"2017_16_11","questionText":"11. In verses 22-24, how and why does God demonstrate His power and mercy?","answer":"","quotes":[]},{"id":"2017_16_12","questionText":"12.  What about the riches of God’s glory move you to prayer, praise or practical actions? (See also Ephesians 1:7-8, 18-23; 2:1-10.)","answer":"","quotes":[{"book":"Ephesians","verse":"1:7-8"},{"book":"Ephesians","verse":"1:18-23"},{"book":"Ephesians","verse":"2:1-10"}]},{"id":"2017_16_13","questionText":"13. What do you learn about God’s mercy and grace to Jews and Gentiles from the Hosea and Isaiah quotations?  (See also Romans 11:3-6.)","answer":"","quotes":[{"book":"Romans","verse":"11:3-6"}]}]},"six":{"title":"SIXTH DAY: Review Romans 9:1-29.","readVerse":[{"book":"Romans","verse":"9:1-29"}],"questions":[{"id":"2017_16_14","questionText":"14. What have you learned about God in this week’s study? How may your group pray for you as you make this truth a part of your life?","answer":"","quotes":[]},{"id":"2017_16_15","questionText":"15. Homiletics for group and administrative leaders: Romans 9:1-29","answer":"","quotes":[{"book":"Romans","verse":"9:1-29"}]}]}}}